原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯     小泡椒  魚小淵  快用六麥神劍  萊吉
時間軸     西查小蛤蜊  紫夏鸚鵡螺  歲半皮皮蝦
時間軸     Jessie小章魚  Ans浪味仙
校對     杏仁斯嘉麗
后期     8T
總監     somehacker
混沌初開之時
In the beginning...
世界只有一片汪洋
there was only ocean...
直到母親島
until the Mother Island emerged.
特菲提出現
Te Fiti.
特菲提之心擁有世上最強大的力量
Her heart held the greatest power ever known.
能夠創造生命
It could create life itself.
特菲提創造了世間一切生命
And Te Fiti shared it with the world.
可不久之后
But in time...
有些人開始尋找特菲提之心
some began to seek Te Fiti's heart.
他們堅信  得到它
They believed if they could possess it...
就能獲得創造一切的強大力量
the great power of creation would be theirs.
有一天
And one day...
這些人中最大膽的一位
the most daring of them all...
跨越浩瀚的海洋去奪取特菲提之心
voyaged across the vast ocean to take it.
他是主宰風與海的半神
He was a demigod of the wind and sea.
他是一名勇士
He was a warrior.
一位魔術師
A trickster.
一個能用他神奇魚鉤的法力
A shapeshifter who could change form...
隨意變換形體的變形者
with the power of his magical fish hook.
他的名字叫作
And his name...
毛伊
was Maui.
但是失去了心之后  特菲提開始瓦解
But without her heart, Te Fiti began to crumble...
創造出了可怕的黑暗
giving birth to a terrible darkness.
毛伊試圖逃走
Maui tried to escape...
但碰上了另一個尋找特菲提之心的人
but was confronted by another who sought the heart.
特卡
Te Ka!
他是土與火的惡魔
A demon of earth and fire.
毛伊被從空中擊中
Maui was struck from the sky...
從此了無蹤跡
never to be seen again.
而他的魔法魚鉤和特菲提之心
And his magical fish hook and the heart of Te Fiti...
一起沉入了大海
were lost to the sea.
即使在一千年之后的今天
Where, even now 1,000 years later...
特卡和深海的惡魔
Te Ka and the demons of the deep
仍在尋找特菲提之心
still hunt for the heart.
他們隱藏在不斷蔓延的黑暗之中
Hiding in a darkness that will continue to spread...
趕跑我們的魚群
chasing away our fish...
侵占一座又一座島嶼
draining the life from island after island...
我們所有人都將
until every one of us is devoured...
被那嗜血的死亡魔爪
by the bloodthirsty jaws...
吞噬殆盡
of inescapable death!
但總有一天
But one day...
會有人找到特菲提之心
the heart will be found...
那個人將駛過環礁  揚帆遠航
by someone who will journey beyond our reef...
找到毛伊
find Maui...
帶他穿洋過海
deliver him across the great ocean...
歸還特菲提之心
to restore Te Fiti's heart...
拯救眾生
and save us all.
謝謝  母親  講到這兒就行了
Thank you, Mother. That's enough.
爸爸
Papa.
誰都不準越過環礁
No one goes outside the reef.
這里很安全  世上沒有黑暗勢力
We are safe here. There is no darkness.
也沒有什么怪獸
There are no monsters.
怪獸  怪獸
Monsters! Monsters!
-不不  沒有怪獸  -黑暗勢力來了
- There's no monsters, no monsters. - It's the darkness!
不  環礁外只有風暴和洶涌的大海
No, there is nothing beyond our reef, but storms and rough seas.
我要吐了
I'm gonna throw up.
只要我們大家都待在這座島上
As long as we stay on our very safe island...
就會很安全
we'll be fine.
傳說都是真的
The legends are true.
一定有人會揚帆遠航的
Someone will have to go.
母親  莫圖魯尼島就是天堂
Mother, Motunui is paradise.
誰還想去別的地方呢
Who would want to go anywhere else?
莫阿娜
Moana!
總算找到你了  莫阿娜
There you are, Moana.
你在做什么  嚇壞我了
What are you doing? You scared me.
干嘛  我想回去
What? I wanna's go back.
我知道  但你不能靠近海邊
I know, I know. But you don't go out there.
那里很危險
It's dangerous.
莫阿娜  走吧
Moana, come on.
我們回村子去
Let's go back to the village.
你是我們族人的下一任偉大的酋長
You are the next great chief of our people.
你會做許多了不起的事  我的小寶貝
And you will do wondrous things, my little minnow.
沒錯  但首先你要清楚自己的所屬之地
Oh, yes. But first, you must learn where you're meant to be.
*莫阿娜駕到*
*Moana*
*大伙  都讓開*
*Make way, make way*
*莫阿娜  你是時候該知曉*
*Moana, it's time you knew*
*你有莫圖魯尼村就已足夠*
*The village of Motunui is all you need*
*舞者們在排練*
*The dancers are practicing*
*伴著古老的歌曲起舞*
*They dance to an ancient song*
*要新歌干嘛  我們只要這首老歌*
*Who needs a new song, this old one's all we need*
*繼承傳統是我們的使命*
*This tradition is our mission*
*莫阿娜  還有很多事要做*
*And Moana, there's so much to do*
*別被芋頭給絆了腳  你有它已足夠*
*Don't trip on the taro root. That's all you need*
*勞動成果  人人共享*
*We share everything we make*
*有說有笑  編織籃子*
*We joke and we weave our baskets*
*漁夫從大海歸來*
*The fishermen come back from the sea*
*我想看看*
*I wanna see*
*別走遠*
*Don't walk away*
*莫阿娜  快快坐下*
*Moana, stay on the ground now*
*族人需要一位酋長*
*Our people will need a chief*
*就是你*
*And there you are*
*終有一天*
*There comes a day*
*當你回首  就會明白真正的幸福*
*When you're gonna look around and realize happiness is*
*就在你的所屬之地*
*Where you are*
*瞧瞧這椰子*
*Consider the coconut*
*什么  瞧瞧這椰樹*
*The what? Consider its tree*
*我們充分利用椰子的每一處  我們有它已足夠*
*We use each part of the coconut. It's all we need*
*纖維制成魚網*
*We make our nets from the fibers*
*椰汁清甜可口*
*The water is sweet inside*
*樹葉生火  椰肉烹調*
*We use the leaves to build fires we cook up the meat inside*
*瞧瞧這些椰子*
*Consider the coconuts*
*這樹干和樹葉*
*The trunks and the leaves*
*小島給予我們所需*
*The island gives us what we need*
*無人離開*
*And no one leaves*
*沒錯  我們留在這里*
*That's right, we stay*
*這里安全又富饒*
*We're safe and we're well-provided*
*未來引導我們之人*
*And when we look to the future*
*就是你*
*There you are*
*不用擔心*
*You'll be okay*
*你會學我所學*
*In time you'll learn just as I did*
*你必須在所屬之地找到幸福*
*You must find happiness right where you are*
*我喜歡隨海浪起舞  伴著潮起潮落*
*I like to dance with the water the undertow and the waves*
*海水十分頑皮  但我就喜歡它淘氣*
*The water is mischievous. I like how it misbehaves*
*村民們可能覺得我瘋了*
*The village may think I'm crazy*
*或者我的思維漂得太遠*
*Or say that I drift too far*
*可一旦你知曉所愛  這才是真正的你*
*But once you know what you like. Well, there you are*
*女兒像爸爸  頑固又驕傲*
*You are your father's daughter stubbornness and pride*
*他的教導自有道理  但你的心聲也許不同*
*Mind what he says but remember, you may hear a voice inside*
*如果你內心輕喃  追隨最遠的那顆星*
*And if the voice starts to whisper to follow the farthest star*
*莫阿娜  那心聲就是真實的你*
*Moana, that voice inside is who you are*
爸爸
Dad!
我只是看看那些船  沒打算登船
I was only looking at the boats. I wasn't gonna get on 'em.
來吧  我給你看樣東西
Come on. There's something I need to show you.
從你出生起
I've wanted to bring you here
我就一直想帶你來這里
from the moment you opened your eyes.
這是個神圣的地方
This is a sacred place.
酋長之地
A place of chiefs.
總有一天
There will come a time...
你會站在這峰頂
when you will stand on this peak
給這座山添上一塊石頭
and place a stone on this mountain.
就像我  我的父親
Like I did. Like my father did.
他的父親  還有每一代酋長都這么做
And his father, and every chief that has ever been.
到那一天
And on that day...
等你把你的石頭放上去
when you add your stone...
你就會讓這座小島變得更高
you will raise this whole island higher.
你是我們族人的未來  莫阿娜
You are the future of our people, Moana.
他們并非遠在天邊
And they are not out there.
而是近在眼前
They are right here.
你是時候該成為他們需要的人了
It's time to be who they need you to be.
*纖維制成魚網*
*We make our nets from the fibers*
*椰汁清涼可口  樹葉生火*
*The water is sweet inside. We use the leaves to build fires*
*大伙一起歌唱*
*We sing these songs in our choirs*
*椰肉烹調  養活族人*
*To cook up the meat inside. We have mouths to feed inside*
*大家都信任我們  沒錯*
*The village believes in us. That's right*
*大家都信任*
*The village believes*
*小島給予我們所需*
*The island gives us what we need*
*無人離開*
*And no one leaves*
*所以我會留在這里*
*So here I'll stay*
*與我的家人族人一起*
*My home, my people beside me*
*當我展望未來之時*
*And when I think of tomorrow*
*我們相伴*
*There we are*
*我會帶領大家*
*I'll lead the way*
*也需要族人指引我*
*I'll have my people to guide me*
*我們會共筑未來*
*We'll build our future together*
*就在此地*
*Where we are*
*因為每條路都會帶你回到*
*'Cause every path leads ya back to*
*你的所屬之地*
*Where you are*
*你會發現幸福就在*
*You can find happiness right*
*你的所屬之地*
*Where you are*
每次風暴過后
And every storm,
無論我鋪了多少樹葉  這屋頂還是漏水
this roof leaks, no matter how many fronds I add.
搞定  不是樹葉的問題
Fixed! Not the fronds.
是風把柱子吹偏了
Wind shifted the post.
這豬肉真好吃
That's good pork!
不是說你  我的意思是
I didn't mean... I wasn't...
什么  他們在叫我  那我先走了
What? They are calling me. So I gotta--. Bye!
你表現得很好
You're doing great.
好了嗎
Is it done yet?
就快了
So close.
我好奇為什么那只雞喜歡啄石頭
I'm curious about that chicken eating the rock.
它看起來好像
He seems to lack the basic intelligence
已經完全喪失理智了
required for pretty much everything.
我們能把它給煮了嗎
Should we maybe just cook him?
有時我們的優點隱藏在外表之下
Sometimes our strengths lie beneath the surface.
某些時候還藏得很深
Far beneath in some cases.
但憨憨一定有我們看不到的過人之處
But I'm sure there's more to Heihei than meets the eye.
這是今天摘的
It's the harvest.
今早  我在剝椰子時發現...
This morning, I was husking the coconuts and...
我們應該砍掉這些病樹
We should clear the diseased trees
然后重新種一片椰子林
and we will start a new grove.
就在那
There.
謝謝  莫阿娜
Thanks, Moana.
她做得真棒
She's doing great.
這活很適合你
This suits you.
酋長
Chief?
有些東西你得瞧瞧
There's something you need to see.
這是我們在東礁湖設的捕魚簍
Our traps in the east lagoon...
捕到的魚越來越少了
they're pulling up less and less fish.
那我們就換個地方捕魚
Then we'll rotate the fishing grounds.
我們試過了  還是沒有魚
We have. There's no fish.
那我們就去島的另一面捕魚
Then we'll fish the far side of the island.
也試過了
We tried.
迎風的那邊呢
The windward side.
還有背風的那邊  淺灘  海峽
And the leeward side, the shallows, the channel.
整個礁湖我們都試過了
We've tried the whole lagoon.
到處都沒有魚
They're just gone.
你試過用另一種魚餌嗎
Have you tried using a different bait?
我覺得不是魚餌的問題  完全沒有魚
I don't think it's the bait. There's no fish.
而且情況越來越糟
It seems like it's getting worse and worse.
當然  我理解你的擔心不無道理
Of course, I understand you have reason for concern.
我會和長老們商量  我確信...
I will talk to the council. I'm sure we...
如果我們去環礁之外捕魚呢
What if we fish beyond the reef?
誰都不準越過環礁
No one goes beyond the reef.
我明白  但如果礁湖里面沒有魚群
I know. But if there are no fish in the lagoon...
-莫阿娜  -而海洋那么大
- Moana. - And there's a whole ocean.
我們要遵守規矩
We have one rule.
那是有魚可捕時的舊規矩
An old rule, when there were fish.
-遵守規矩我們才安全  -可是  爸爸
- A rule that keeps us safe... - But Dad...
不準你為了能再次靠近大海
Instead of endangering our people
而使我們的族人身陷危險
so you can run right back to the water.
我還以為你早放棄了那個念頭...
Every time I think you're past this...
誰都不能越過環礁
No one goes beyond the reef!
你不該當著你爸的面說出來
Well, it's not like you said it in front of your dad.
還站在船上
Standing on a boat.
我又沒說"到環礁之外捕魚
I didn't say go beyond the reef,
因為我想在海上航行"
because I want to be on the ocean.
但你確實想去
But you still do.
-他對你嚴厲是因為  -因為他不懂我
- He's hard on you because... - Because he doesn't get me.
因為他曾經和你一樣
Because he was you.
被大海所吸引
Drawn to the ocean.
漫步在沙灘
Down by the shore.
他曾駕駛獨木舟  莫阿娜
He took a canoe, Moana.
他穿越環礁
He crossed the reef...
駛入了一片危險的海域
and found an unforgiving sea.
海浪如山一樣高
Waves like mountains.
他最好的朋友懇求他  出海時帶上他
His best friend begged to be on that boat.
你爸爸卻沒能救回他
Your dad couldn't save him.
他希望自己能夠救你
He's hoping he can save you.
有時候
Sometimes...
我們想要成為誰  想做什么事
who we wish we were, what we wish we could do...
并不一定能夠如愿
it's just not meant to be.
*從很久前我就喜歡眺望*
*I've been staring at the edge of the water*
*海平面的盡頭*
*Long as I can remember*
*卻從不明白原因*
*Never really knowing why*
*我希望能做個聽話的女兒*
*I wish I could be the perfect daughter*
*但無論我如何努力*
*But I come back to the water*
*都還是回到這海洋*
*No matter how hard I try*
*經過每個轉彎  走過每條小徑*
*Every turn I take, every trail I track*
*踏過每條小路  都引領我回到*
*Every path I make, every road leads back*
*那個我不能去*
*To the place I know where I cannot go*
*卻無比向往的地方*
*Where I long to be*
*看那海天相接*
*See the line where the sky meets the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*It calls me*
*有誰知道*
*And no one knows*
*它延伸到多遠*
*How far it goes*
*如果海風助我  揚帆起航*
*If the wind in my sail on the sea stays behind me*
*我終會知道*
*One day I'll know*
*若我啟程  前途無限*
*If I go, there's just no telling how far I'll go*
*我知道這座島上的每個人*
*I know everybody on this island*
*似乎對島上生活快樂無憂*
*Seems so happy on this island*
*一切早已安排好*
*Everything is by design*
*我知道這座島上的每個人*
*I know everybody on this island*
*都有自己的在島上的職責*
*Has a role on this island*
*所以或許我也該坦然接受*
*So maybe I can roll with mine*
*我可以驕傲地領導  讓部族更強*
*I can lead with pride I can make us strong*
*若我遵循傳統  應該也會心滿意足*
*I'll be satisfied if I play along*
*但心里卻一直唱著另一首歌*
*But the voice inside sings a different song*
*我這是怎么了*
*What is wrong with me*
*看遠方海上陽光閃耀*
*See the light as it shines on the sea*
*令人目眩*
*It's blinding*
*有誰知道*
*But no one knows*
*它能照到多深*
*How deep it goes*
*似乎在呼喚我*
*And it seems like it's calling out to me*
*來找我吧*
*So come find me*
*我想知道*
*And let me know*
*海平線外面的世界  我能否穿過海平線*
*What's beyond that line will I cross that line*
*看那海天相接*
*The line where the sky meets the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*It calls me*
*有誰知道*
*And no one knows*
*它延伸到多遠*
*How far it goes*
*如果海風助我  揚帆起航*
*If the wind in my sail on the sea stays behind me*
*我終會知道*
*One day I'll know*
*我將遠行何方*
*How far I'll go*
沒事  胖胖
We're okay, Pua.
我能搞定
I can do this.
環礁外肯定有更多魚
There's more fish beyond the reef.
肯定有的
There's more beyond the reef.
不算糟嘛
Not so bad.
胖胖
Pua!
不管剛剛發生了什么
Whatever just happened...
就說是這頭豬干的
blame it on the pig.
奶奶
Gramma.
你會告訴爸嗎
Are you gonna tell dad?
我是他媽  不用向他匯報
I'm his mom. I don't have to tell him anything.
他說得沒錯
He was right.
外面很危險
About going out there.
是時候把我的石頭放在山上了
It's time to put my stone on the mountain.
好啊  你回去吧
Okay. Well, then, head on back.
把石頭放上去吧
Put that stone up there.
你怎么不勸我
Why aren't you trying to talk me out of it?
你不是說那就是你想要的嗎
You said that's what you wanted.
沒錯
It is.
我死之后...
When I die...
我要作為它們中的一員回歸
I'm going to come back as one of these.
否則我這紋身就白紋了
Or I chose the wrong tattoo.
你怎么怪怪的
Why are you acting weird?
我是村里的怪奶奶呀  這就是我的工作
I'm the village crazy lady. That's my job.
如果你有什么想告訴我的  盡管直說
If there's something you want to tell me, just tell me!
你有什么想告訴我的嗎
Is there something you wanna tell me?
你有什么想聽的嗎
Is there something you want to hear?
我們族人所有的故事你都聽過了
You've been told all our people's stories...
這個除外
but one.
這是什么地方
What is this place?
你真以為我們的祖先一直待在環礁以內嗎
Do you really think our ancestors stayed within the reef?
里面是什么
What's in there?
是你一直以來想不通的問題的答案
The answer to the question you keep asking yourself.
你注定會成為誰
Who are you meant to be?
進去吧...
Go inside...
敲敲鼓...
bang the drum...
你就會知道
and find out.
對了  敲鼓
Bang the drum.
*我們辨風向  讀天相*
*We read the wind and the sky*
*日懸中天時*
*When the sun is high*
*乘風破浪走*
*We sail the length of the seas*
*穿洋過海行*
*On the ocean breeze*
*夜里指認每顆星星*
*At night we name every star*
*知道自己在何方*
*We know where we are*
*知道自己是誰  自己是誰*
*We know who we are who we are*
*我們啟航漫游*
*We set a course to find*
*尋找新的家園*
*A brand new island everywhere we roam*
*故土永在心中*
*We keep our island in our mind*
*故土永在心中  念時即能歸鄉*
*And when it's time to find home we know the way*
*我們是解讀一切的探險家*
*We are explorers reading every sign*
*我們的故事世代相傳  永不終結*
*We tell the stories of our elders in a never-ending chain*
*我們認得回家的路*
*We know the way*
我們曾是航海者
We were voyagers.
We were voyagers!
我們曾是航海者  我們曾是航海者
We were voyagers! We were voyagers!
我們曾是航海者
We were voyagers!
為什么不航海了
Why'd we stop?
是毛伊
Maui.
自從他從母親島偷走了特菲提之心
When he stole from the Mother Island,
黑暗降臨
darkness fell.
特卡蘇醒了
Te Ka awoke.
四處怪物潛伏  吞沒船只
Monsters lurked and boats stopped coming back.
為了保護族人  歷代酋長都禁止出航
To protect our people, the ancient chiefs forbid voyaging...
現在我們已經忘了自己是航海者的后代了
and now we have forgotten who we are.
黑暗還在繼續蔓延...
And the darkness has continued to spread...
趕跑我們的魚群...
chasing away our fish...
吸干一座又一座島嶼上的生命
draining the life...from island after island.
我們的小島
Our island.
但是  總有一天...
But, one day...
有人會越過我們的環礁  找到毛伊
someone will journey beyond our reef, find Maui...
帶他穿洋過海
deliver him across the great ocean...
歸還特菲提之心
to restore the heart of Te Fiti.
那天的事我看到了
I was there that day.
大海選擇了你
The ocean chose you.
我還以為那是個夢
I thought it was a dream.
不
Nope!
我們的祖先相信毛伊就在那里...
Our ancestors believed Maui lies there...
在他的魚鉤下面
at the bottom of his hook.
跟著魚鉤狀星座  你就會找到他
Follow it, and you will find him.
可為什么它選擇的是我
But why would it choose me?
我甚至不知道怎么駕船駛過環礁
I don't even know how to make it past the reef.
不過我知道誰能
But I know who does!
-莊稼變黑了  -魚呢
- The crops are turning black. - What about the fish?
整個島都這樣
This is happening all over the island.
-各位  請先冷靜  -你要怎么做
- Please, please settle down. - What are you going to do?
我們開墾新土地  總會找到辦法...
We will dig new fields. We will find a way to...
我們可以阻止黑暗  拯救我們的小島
We can stop the darkness! Save our island!
我發現一個停滿了船的洞穴
There's a cavern of boats.
巨大的獨木舟
Huge canoes.
我們可以乘這些船  找到毛伊
We can take them, find Maui,
讓他歸還特菲提之心
make him restore the heart.
我們曾是航海者  我們可以再次出海
We were voyagers. We can voyage again!
是你告訴我要幫助族人
You told me to help our people.
只有這樣才能幫助他們
This is how we help our people.
爸爸
Dad?
你要干嗎
What are you doing?
我早就該一把火燒了那些船
I should've burned those boats a long time ago!
不  不要
No! Don't!
我們必須找到毛伊
We have to find Maui.
我們必須歸還特菲提之心
We have to restore the heart!
沒有什么心
There is no heart!
這就是塊破石頭
This is just a rock!
不要
No!
酋長  您母親出事了
Chief! It's your mother!
母親...
Mother...
我們可以做什么
What can be done?
快去
Go-
奶奶
Gramma.
快去
Go-
現在不行
Not now. I can't.
你必須去
You must!
大海選擇了你
The ocean chose you.
跟著魚鉤狀星座走
Follow the fish hook.
奶奶...
Gramma...
等你找到了毛伊...
And when you find Maui...
你就揪著他的耳朵說...
you grab him by the ear. You say...
"我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
"I am Moana of Motunui.
"你必須跟我上船
"You will board my boat...
"穿過大海
"Sail across the sea...
"歸還特菲提之心"
"And restore the heart of Te Fiti."
我不要離開你
I can't leave you.
無論你去哪里  我都陪在你身邊
There is nowhere you could go that I won't be with you.
快去
Go!
*看那海天相接*
*There's a line where the sky meets the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*And it calls me*
*有誰知道*
*But no one knows*
*它延伸到多遠*
*How far it goes*
*所屬之地  困惑不再*
*All that time wondering where I need to be is behind me*
*全靠我自己*
*I'm on my own*
*去向未知天地*
*To worlds unknown*
*經過每個轉彎  走過每條小徑*
*Every turn I take every trail I track*
*都是我的選擇*
*Is a choice I make*
*現在我無法回頭  直面浩渺未知*
*Now I can't turn back from the great unknown*
*獨自前往  心之所向*
*Where I go alone where I long to be*
*看她照亮夜之海*
*See her light up the night in the sea*
*她在呼喚我*
*She calls me*
*是的  我知道*
*And yes, I know*
*我可以揚帆遠航*
*That I can go*
*明月懸空  我迎著海風*
*There's a moon in the sky and the wind is behind me*
*很快就會知道*
*Soon I'll know*
*我將遠行何方*
*How far I'll go*
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
你必須跟我上船
You will board my boat...
穿過大海  歸還特菲提之心
sail across the sea and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
我是莫圖魯尼島的...
I am Moana...
莫阿...
of Motu...
...娜
...nui.
憨憨
Heihei?
別怕  沒事的
It's okay. You're all right.
你看
See?
是吧  多友好的海水
There we go. Nice water.
大海是我的朋友
The ocean is a friend of mine.
憨憨
Heihei?
Heihei!
別動
Stay.
好了  下一站  毛伊
Okay. Next stop, Maui.
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
你必須跟我上船...
You will board my boat...
穿...過大海...
sail... across the sea...
歸還特菲提之心
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫...
I am Moana of Motu...
跟我上船
Board my boat!
不
Oh, no...
不不不
No, no, no!
大海...
Ocean...
能不能幫幫我
can I get a little help?
不不
No, no.
拜托  快點
Please. Come on!
幫幫我  求你了
Help me! Please!
怎么回事
What?
我說幫幫我
I said help me!
你卻毀了我的船
And wrecking my boat?
幫倒忙
Not helping!
活該魚群天天在你里面尿尿
Fish pee in you all day!
那
So...
毛伊
Maui?
Maui!
毛伊  主宰風與海的半神...
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea...
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
你跟我上船
You will board my boat.
不  你必須跟我上船
No. You will board my boat.
對  我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
Yeah. I am Moana of Motunui.
你必須...
You will board my...
船  一艘船
Boat! A boat!
諸神賜給我一艘...
The gods have given me a...
毛伊  變形者...
Maui, shapeshifter...
主宰風與海的半神...
demigod of the wind and sea...
-我是莫圖魯尼島的  -人類的英雄
- I am Moana of... - Hero of men.
什么
What?
全稱是  毛伊  變形者
It's actually, Maui, shapeshifter,
主宰風與海的半神  人類的英雄
demigod of the wind and sea...hero of men.
我打斷你了  你從頭再來
I interrupted. From the top.
加上人類的英雄  說吧
Hero of men. Go.
我是...
I am...
抱歉  抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
還有女人  是男人和女人的英雄
And women. Men and women.
對兩種性別都是  對所有人都是  不論男女
Both. All. Not a guy, girl thing.
畢竟毛伊是所有人的英雄
You know, Maui is a hero to all.
你說得不錯
You're doing great.
什么  不  我來這是...
What? No! I'm here to...
當然  當然
Of course. Of course.
對對對
Yes, yes, yes.
毛伊對粉絲永遠有耐心
Maui always has time for his fans.
如果你用一只鳥來寫字...
When you use a bird to write with...
tweet既可指發推特也可指鳥吱吱叫
就叫發推
it's called tweeting.
我知道  英雄不是隨隨便便就能見到的
I know, not every day you get a chance to meet your hero.
你不是我的英雄
You are not my hero.
我來這不是讓你在我槳上簽名的
And I'm not here so you can sign my oar!
我來這是因為你偷了特菲提之心
I'm here 'cause you stole the heart of Te Fiti!
你必須跟我上船
And you will board my boat...
穿過大海  把它還回去
and sail across the sea and put it back!
聽起簡直就像你不喜歡我...
Yeah, it almost sounded like you don't like me...
不過這不可能...
which is impossible because...
我被困在這里一千年
I got stuck here for 1,000 years...
就是為了把這顆心當禮物送給你們凡人
trying to get the heart as a gift for you mortals.
你們就能擁有創造生命的力量
So you could have the power to create life itself.
所以我相信你想說的應該是
Yeah. So, what I believe you were trying to say...
"謝謝"
is "Thank you."
-"謝謝"  -不客氣
- "Thank you?" - You're welcome.
什么  不不不
What? No, no, no!
我不是  不是
I didn't... I wasn't...
為什么我要說謝謝
Why would I ever say that? I mean.
好啦好啦
Okay, okay.
*我知道是什么情況了*
*I see what's happening yeah*
*你面對我這種偉大  感覺很怪*
*You're face to face with greatness and it's strange*
*你不明白自己什么感受*
*You don't even know how you feel*
*真是傻得可愛*
*It's adorable*
*人類沒什么變化真是太好了*
*Well it's nice to see that humans never change*
*睜大你的眼睛  開始吧*
*Open your eyes let's begin*
*沒錯就是我*
*Yes, it's really me*
*保持冷靜  正是我毛伊*
*It's Maui breathe it in*
*我知道這是重大驚喜*
*I know it's a lot*
*我的秀發  健體*
*The hair the bod*
*當你正看著一位半神*
*When you're staring at a demigod*
*我只能說*
*What can I say except*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*不需為了潮汐  太陽和天空感謝我*
*For the tides, the sun, the sky*
*小事一樁  別客氣*
*Hey, it's okay, it's okay you're welcome*
*我只是個平凡的半神*
*I'm just an ordinary demiguy*
*是誰用雙手撐起天空*
*What has two thumbs and pulled up the sky*
*當你還蹣跚學步*
*When you were waddling yay high?*
*正是在下*
*This guy*
*當夜晚寒冷  誰為你偷來火焰*
*When the nights got cold who stole you fire from down below?*
*正是你看著的在下*
*You're looking at him*
*我還套住了太陽*
*Also I lassoed the sun*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*只是為了延長白天  給你們帶來歡樂*
*To stretch your days and bring you fun*
*我還利用海風*
*Also I harnessed the breeze*
*別客氣*
You're welcome
*推動帆船  搖晃樹木*
*To fill your sails and shake your trees*
*除了別客氣我還能說什么*
*So what can I say except you're welcome*
*不需因為我升起島嶼而謝我*
*For the islands I pulled from the sea*
*不需向我頂禮膜拜*
*There's no need to pray it's okay*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*我就是這么一個助人為樂的好心人*
*I guess it's just my way of being me*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*其實想一想*
*Well come to think of it*
*孩子  我能滔滔不絕地說下去*
*Kid, honestly I could go on and on*
*我可以解釋所有的自然現象*
*I could explain every natural phenomenon*
*潮汐  草地  土地*
*The tide, the grass the ground*
*只是毛伊隨手做的小貢獻*
*That was Maui just messing around*
*我殺了條鰻魚  埋下它的內臟*
*I killed an eel I buried its guts*
*樹從地里長出來  你們才有了椰子*
*Sprouted a tree now you got coconuts*
*什么是教訓  什么是代價*
*What's the lesson? What is the take away?*
*毛伊一出手  千萬別惹他*
*Don't mess with Maui when he's on a breakaway*
*我身上的紋身*
*And the tapestry here on my skin*
*就是我勝利的地圖*
*Is a map of the victories I win*
*我所到之處  創造萬物*
*Look where I've been I make everything happen*
*看這只小小毛伊踢踏起舞*
*Look at that Mean Mini-Maui just tickety tappin'*
*讓我說  別客氣*
*Well anyway let me say you're welcome*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*不需為了花花世界謝我*
*For the wonderful world you know*
*小事一樁  別客氣*
*Hey, it's okay, it's okay you're welcome*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*轉念一想  我得走了*
*Well come to think of it I gotta go*
*今天輪到你說別客氣*
*Hey it's your day to say you're welcome*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*因為我得用你的那條船*
*'Cause I'm gonna need that boat*
*我要啟航  別客氣*
*I'm sailing away away you're welcome*
*別客氣*
*You're welcome*
*毛伊除了水上漂  什么都能做到*
*'Cause Maui can do everything but float*
*別客氣  別客氣*
*You're welcome you're welcome*
謝謝你
And thank you!
讓我出去  你這個滿嘴謊言的大騙...
Let me out! You lying, slimy son of a...
別客氣
You're welcome.
真的別客氣
You're so welcome.
不  我才不會和一個孩子去特菲提
No. I'm not going to Te Fiti with some kid.
我要去拿我的魚鉤
I'm going to get my hook.
你的魚鉤還在  我沒有魚鉤就不是毛伊了
You have yours and I'm not Maui without mine.
好了  去后面吧
Okay, talk to the back.
船上零食
Boat snack.
再見了  這一堆臭石頭
Good riddance, you filthy pile of pebbles.
不不不  別這樣看著我
Oh, no, no, no. Don't look at me like that.
那是個漂亮的山洞  她會喜歡的
It's a beautiful cave. She's gonna love it.
我會在我的肚子里好好疼愛你的
And I'm going to love you in ma belly.
現在先把你養肥一點吧  小雞腿
Now, let's fatten you up, drumstick.
剛才那一幕我能循環看一天
I could watch that all day.
好了  好好享受這座島吧
Okay. Enjoy the island.
毛伊走也
Maui, out.
不  停下
No! Stop!
你得把心石放回去
You have to put back the heart!
還真是出乎意料
Did not see that coming.
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
這是我的獨木舟
This is my canoe...
你將和我一起
and you will journey to...
好  忘了她吧  我們得走了
All right, get over it. We gotta move.
然后她又回來了
And she's back.
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui...
你叫莫阿娜  對吧
It was Moana, right?
是的
Yes.
你得去歸還心石
And you will restore the heart!
好吧  我退出
All right. I'm out.
拜托
Oh, come on!
你怎么了
What is your problem?
你很害怕它嗎
Are you afraid of it?
不  不
No! No.
我不害怕
I'm not afraid.
別摻和  不然我就讓你睡在我的腋窩里
Stay out of it or you're sleeping in my armpit.
你別鬧了
You, stop it.
這不是一顆心  這是詛咒
That is not a heart. It is a curse.
我一拿到它  就被炸飛到九霄云外
The second I took it, I got blasted outta the sky...
還丟了我的魚鉤
and I lost my hook.
把它拿走
Get it away from me.
把這個拿走嗎
Get this away?
我可是個半神好嗎
I'm a demigod, okay?
停下  我會懲罰你的
Stop that. I will smite you!
你想被乘法嗎
You wanna get smote?
還是承乏
Smotten?
聽著  這東西才不會給你創造生命的力量
Listen, that thing doesn't give you power to create life...
它會招致死亡
it's a homing beacon of death.
如果你不扔掉它  壞事會找上門的
If you don't put it away, bad things are gonna come for it.
因為這個嗎  心石
Come for this? The heart?
你是指這里的這塊心石嗎
You mean this heart right here?
別  你不要這樣大聲說話
Don't, you can't raise your voice like that!
快來拿吧
Come and get it!
你會害死我們的
You are gonna get us killed!
不  我會讓我們安全到達特菲提讓你歸還心石
No, I'm gonna get us to Te Fiti, so you can put it back.
謝謝你
Thank you.
別客氣
You're welcome.
卡卡莫拉
Kakamora.
卡卡什么
Kaka-what?
兇殘的小海盜
Murdering little pirates.
真想不通他們為什么而來
Wonder what they're here for.
他們有點可愛啊
They're kinda cute.
大海
Ocean!
快幫幫我們
Do something! Help us!
海洋不會幫你  你得自救
The ocean doesn't help you, you help yourself!
拉緊吊索  捆好側支索
Tighten the halyard. Bind the stays!
你不會駕船
You can't sail?
我
I...
我是自學成才的
I am self-taught.
你不是能變形什么的嗎
Can't you shapeshift or something?
你看見我的魚鉤了嗎
Do you see my hook?
沒有魔法魚鉤  我就沒有魔法
No magic hook, no magic powers!
他們一條船分成了好幾條
Their boat is turning into more boats!
沒錯  我做到了
Yep, I just did that.
不不
No, no!
憨憨
Heihei!
毛伊
Maui!
他們拿走了心石
They took the heart!
那是只雞
That's a chicken.
心石就在那只雞的
The heart is in the...
我們得把雞救回來
We have to get him back!
毛伊
Maui!
那兒  就在那兒
There! Right there!
你要掉頭
You're turning?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
逃跑啊
Escaping!
心石[心形]
The heart!
算了吧  你拿不回來的
Forget it! You'll never get it back!
再說了 你有一顆更好的
Besides, you got a better one.
我要用什么控制船
What am I gonna steer with?
他們會殺了你的
They're just gonna kill ya!
小椰子
Coconuts.
拿到了
Got it!
我們做到了
We did it!
恭喜你沒死  小姑娘
Congratulations on not being dead, girlie.
你真讓我吃驚
You surprise me.
但我還是不會把那玩意還回去的
But I'm still not taking that thing back.
你要去特菲提
You wanna get to Te Fiti
得穿過整個兇險的海洋
you gotta go through a whole ocean of bad.
更別說特卡的阻擋了
Not to mention Te Ka.
巖漿怪
Lava monster?
你打敗過巖漿怪嗎
Ever defeat a lava monster?
沒有  你呢
No. Have you?
我才不會和一個凡人去送死
I'm not going on a suicide mission with some mortal.
你沒我可歸還不了心石
You can't restore the heart without me...
而我是拒絕的
and me says no.
我要去拿回魚鉤
I'm getting my hook.
討論到此為止
End of discussion.
你會成為一位英雄的
You'd be a hero.
那是你人生的意義  不是嗎
That's what you're all about, right?
小姑娘  我已經是英雄了
Little girl, I am a hero.
也許你曾經是
Maybe you were.
但現在
But now...
現在你只是偷了特菲提之心的那個家伙
now you're just the guy who stole the heart of Te Fiti.
那個毀了世界的家伙
The guy who cursed the world.
沒人覺得你是英雄
You're no one's hero.
沒人
No one?
但是呢
But...
把這個還回去
put this back...
拯救世界
save the world...
你就會成為所有人的英雄
you'd be everyone's hero.
毛伊  毛伊  毛伊
Maui! Maui! Maui!
你真了不起
You're so amazing!
沒有我的魚鉤做不到  過不了特卡那關
We'd never make it without my hook. Not past Te Ka.
那我們就去拿你的魚鉤
Then we get your hook.
拿回你的魚鉤  打倒特卡  歸還心石
We get your hook, take out Te Ka, restore the heart.
除非你不想成為
Unless you don't wanna be...
毛伊  主宰風與海的半神
Maui, demigod of the wind and sea.
全民
Hero to...
英雄
all.
首先  我們去拿回魚鉤
First, we get my hook.
然后拯救世界
Then save the world.
說好了
Deal?
Deal.
試試總沒錯嘛
Worth a shot.
好  我們往東走
Okay, we go east.
去螃蟹怪的老巢
To the lair of Tamatoa.
一定是那個珠子眼吃泥蟲拿了我的魚鉤
If anyone has my hook, it's that beady-eyed bottom-feeder.
教我駕船吧
Teach me to sail.
我的使命是帶毛伊穿洋過海
My job is to deliver Maui across the great ocean.
應該
I should...
應該我來駕船
I should be sailing.
這叫規劃導航  小公主
It's called wayfinding, princess.
可不止是駕船和打結
And it's not just sails and knots...
而是在腦海中清晰看見你在往哪走
it's seeing where you're going in your mind.
用你曾經的位置
Knowing where you are...
推斷出你現在在哪
by knowing where you've been.
首先  我不是公主
Okay, first, I'm not a princess.
我是酋長的女兒
I am the daughter of the chief.
-沒差  -不是
- Same difference. - No.
你穿著裙子  還有個動物伙伴
If you wear a dress, and you have an animal sidekick...
你就是個公主
you're a princess.
你可不是個規劃導航家
You are not a wayfinder.
也永遠不可能成為一個規劃導航家  永遠不
You will never be a wayfinder, you will never be a...
不是吧  往我的屁股蛋上插飛鏢
Really? Blow dart in my butt cheek?
你是個壞人
You are a bad person.
你能說話  就能教我
If you can talk, you can teach.
規劃導航
Wayfinding.
第一課  開始吧
Lesson one. Hit it.
把船帆拉起來
Pull the sheet.
不是那個
Not the sheet.
不是
No.
Nope.
不是  不是
Nope.No.
那個已經試過了
Tried that one already.
你是要測量星辰  不是跟天空擊掌
You're measuring the stars, not giving the sky a high-five.
如果海流是溫的  你就走對路了
If the current's warm, you're going the right way.
是涼的
It's cold.
等下  現在變暖了
Wait, it's getting warmer.
太惡心了  你有什么毛病
That is disgusting! What is wrong with you?
我們到了
We're here?
看  告訴過你我能做到的
See, told you I could do it!
莫圖魯尼島
Motunui?
我這是回家了嗎
I'm home?
-莫阿娜  -爸爸
- Moana! - Dad?
莫阿娜
Moana!
媽媽
Mom?
救救我們
Help!
不
No!
莫阿娜
Moana!
美容覺睡得還滿意嗎
Enjoy your beauty rest?
要知道一個真的規劃導航家從不休息
You know, a real wayfinder never sleeps...
這樣他們才能到達目的地
so they actually get where they need to go.
活動一下吧  寶貝
Muscle up, buttercup.
我們到了
We're here.
你確定魚鉤在他那里嗎
You're sure this guy's gonna have your hook?
螃蟹怪  他會有的
Tamatoa? Oh, he'll have it.
他喜歡撿破爛
He's a scavenger.
覺得收集東西能讓他顯得很酷
Collects stuff. Thinks it makes him look cool.
所以對于螃蟹怪來說  相信我
And for Tamatoa, trust me...
我的魚鉤一定是最酷的收藏品
my hook is the coolest collectible.
他住在這上面嗎
And he lives up there?
不  不  不
No, no, no.
這只是個入口
That's just the entrance...
去拉羅泰
to Lalotai.
拉羅泰
Lalotai?
怪物王國
Realm of monsters?
我們這是要去怪物王國嗎
We're going to the realm of monsters?
我們  不  只有我
We? No. Me.
你和另外一只雞就待在這里
You are gonna stay here with the other chicken.
我就是這個意思  來擊個掌
That's what I'm talking about. Gimme some.
這不挺好笑的嘛  你怎么不懂我的梗呢
Come on. That was a good one. How do you not get it?
我叫她弱雞  正好船上還有只真的雞
I called her a chicken, there's a chicken on the boat.
我知道她是人類  但這不是重...
I know she's human, but that's not the...
算了  算了
You know what? Forget it. Forget it!
不跟你解釋了
I'm not explaining it to you.
說穿了就不好玩了
'Cause then it's not funny.
那么  酋長女兒
So, daughter of the chief...
我還以為你會安心待在村莊里
I thought you stayed in the village.
安撫小屁孩之類的
You know, kissing babies and things.
我只是想試著理解
Hey, I'm just trying to understand...
為什么你的族人會派...
why your people decided to send...
怎么說呢  你
How do I phrase this? You.
不是我的族人派我來的
My people didn't send me.
大海選擇了我
The ocean did.
大海
The ocean?
真說得通
Makes sense.
你才八歲  還不會駕船
You're what, eight? Can't sail.
好一個不二人選
Obvious choice.
選我總有它自己的理由
It chose me for a reason.
假如大海真這么聰明
If the ocean's so smart...
為什么不自己動手把心石送回特菲提
why didn't it just take the heart back to Te Fiti itself?
把魚鉤還給我也行啊
Or bring me my hook?
這大海的名堂還真多
The ocean's straight up kooky-docks.
但選你肯定是沒錯的
But I'm sure it's not wrong about you.
你可是被選中的人
You're the Chosen One!
海洋選你自有它的理由
The ocean chose you for a reason.
你要是唱歌的話  我會吐的
If you start singing, I'm gonna throw up.
我沒看到有入口啊
So, not seeing an entrance.
那當然  入口要出現的話
Yes, because it only appears...
必須得用人祭祀
after a human sacrifice.
開玩笑啦
Kidding.
你也太當真了
So serious.
別擔心
Don't worry...
這比看上去還要深得多
it's a lot farther down than it looks.
我還在往下掉
I am still falling!
你能做到的
You can do this.
來吧
Go!
滿分著陸
And he sticks the landing.
什么  傻了吧你  她都沒在好吧
What? Bum-Gum, she's not even here.
沒有凡人會跳進這個怪物...
No mortal's gonna jump into the realm of...
她死了
Well, she's dead.
走吧  去拿回我的魚鉤
Okay, let's get my hook.
毛伊的魚鉤
Maui's fishhook!
對呀
Yeah!
對不起
Sorry!
我還以為你是個怪物
I thought you were a monster...
不過我找到了你的魚鉤
But I found your hook.
你說得對  螃蟹怪真的視財如命
And, you're right, this Tamatoa guy really likes his treasure.
待著
Stay.
什么  我才是那個發現了...
What? No. I'm the one who found...
聽著  一千年來
Listen. For a thousand years...
我只思考怎么讓頭發保持柔順
I've only been thinking of keeping this hair silky...
怎么拿回魚鉤
getting my hook...
以及怎么東山再起
and being awesome again.
我是絕不會讓一個凡人搞砸的
And it's not getting screwed up by a mortal...
更何況她對怪物洞穴一無所知  除非
who has no business inside of a monster cave, except...
除非...
except...
她當個誘餌
maybe as bait.
金光閃閃的洞穴啊
The shiny, glittery cave.
正好和我一樣
And just like me...
被耀眼的珍寶重重包裹著
it is covered in sparkly treasure.
一閃一閃  亮晶晶
Sparkle, sparkle, sparkle.
你這樣沒人信的
You're not selling it!
這蠢到家了  不如我直接走上去拿下來
This is stupid! I'm just gonna walk up and get it!
你上去的話他會殺了你的  照原計劃來
You go up there, he will kill you. Just stick to the plan.
他現身之后  一直吸引他注意力
When he shows up, keep him distracted.
讓他說說他自己
Make him talk about himself.
他特別喜歡臭顯擺
He loves bragging about how great he is.
那你倆應該很合得來了
You two must get along swell.
是啊  直到我扯斷了他的一條腿
No, not since I ripped off his leg.
你扯斷了他的...
You ripped off his...
毛伊
Maui?
看我找到了什么
What have we here?
一個金光閃閃的...  等等
It's a sparkly, shiny... Wait a minute.
一個人類
It's a human!
你下來這里干什么  在這個怪物...
What are you doing down here, in the realm of the...
隨便選一只眼睛盯吧
Just pick an eye, babe.
你這樣晃得我沒法集中注意力說話
I can't concentrate on what I'm saying if you keep...
隨便選個  選一個
Yeah, pick one, pick one!
你這小家伙看上去可真奇怪
You're a funny-looking little thing, aren't you?
別碰  那是我奶奶的
Don't! That's my gramma's!
"那是我奶奶的"
"That's my gramma's!"
我奶奶被我吃了
I ate my gramma!
我足足吃了一周  因為她太大了
And it took a week, 'cause she was absolutely humongous.
你來這里干什么
Why are you here?
因為你太不可思議了
'Cause you're amazing!
我們凡人曾聽說過你的故事
And we mortals have heard
一只了不起的螃蟹成了傳奇
of the tale of the crab who became a legend!
我只是想知道
And I just had to know...
您是怎么變得這么
how you became so...
蚌極了的
crabulous?
你是想讓我談談我自己嗎
Are you just trying to get me to talk about myself?
假如是的話
Because if you are...
那我太樂意了
I will gladly do so.
讓我唱給你聽
In song form!
*螃蟹怪之前并非如此魅力四射*
*Well, Tamatoa hasn't always been this glam*
*我也曾是無名小蟹*
*I was a drab little crab once*
*而如今的我笑容燦爛*
*Now I know I can be happy as a clam*
*只因我美麗又動人*
*Because I'm beautiful, baby*
*你奶奶是否曾說*
*And did your granny say*
*聆聽自己的心聲*
*Listen to your heart*
*勇敢做心中的自己*
*Be who you are on the inside*
*我用三個詞就能推翻她*
*I need three words to tear her argument apart*
*你  奶奶  騙人*
*Your granny lied*
*我寧可絢麗奪目*
*I'd rather be shiny*
*如同那海盜的沉船寶藏*
*Like a treasure from a sunken pirate wreck*
*把甲板洗刷得閃閃發亮吧*
*Scrub the deck and make it look shiny*
*我會像貴婦的項鏈一般閃耀*
*I will sparkle like a wealthy woman's neck*
*只需一秒  你難道不知道嗎*
*Just a sec don't ya know*
*魚兒們蠢  蠢  蠢  追逐一切發光體*
*Fish are dumb, dumb, dumb they chase anything that glitters*
*太幼稚*
*Beginners*
*現在他們向我沖  沖  沖*
*And here they come, come, come*
*只因我是最奪目的光源*
*To the brightest thing that glitters*
*魚肉晚餐*
*Fish dinners*
*我就是喜歡送上門來的*
*I just love free food*
*你看上去也像海鮮大餐*
*And you look like seafood*
不
No!
蟹肉餅
Hey,  crab cake!
我回來了
I'm back.
輪到毛伊上場了
It's Maui Time!
變什么好呢  小家伙
What do you say, little buddy?
巨鷹嗎  那就來吧
Giant hawk? Coming up!
哎呦呦
Well, well, well.
*小毛伊的變形術不聽使喚啦*
*Little Maui's having trouble with his look*
*你這個小半神*
*Ya little semi-demi-mini-god*
*表現可真糟糕*
*What a terrible performance*
*拿到魚鉤又怎樣*
*Get the hook get it?*
*你早已不復當年了  老兄*
*You don't swing it like you used to, man*
*但謝謝你成就了現在的我*
*Yet I have to give you credit for my start*
*還有你身上的紋身*
*And your tattoos on the outside*
*我也學著你把自己裝飾成藝術品*
*For just like you I made myself a work of art*
*我不會躲藏  也藏不住*
*I'll never hide I can't*
*我是如此閃耀*
*I'm too shiny*
*像璞玉一般耀眼奪目*
*Watch me dazzle like a diamond in the rough*
*誰讓它們如此金光閃閃*
*Strut my stuff my stuff is so shiny*
*你盡管出招  都是螳臂當車而已*
*Send your armies but they'll never be enough*
*我的外殼是如此堅硬  毛伊*
*My Shell's too tough Maui, man*
*你盡管來呀  來呀  來呀  但別指望一個半神*
*You can try, try, try but you can't expect a demigod*
*打敗一個多足怪  走著瞧*
*To beat a decapod look it up*
*你馬上就死啦  死啦  死啦*
*You will die, die, die*
*讓我來粉碎*
*Now it's time for me to take apart*
*你那脆弱的小心靈吧*
*Your achin' heart*
*遠離那些曾拋棄你的人*
*Far from the ones who abandoned you*
*追求著人類的愛*
*Chasing the love of these humans*
*讓你自己覺得被需要*
*Who made you feel wanted*
*你也曾試著堅強*
*You tried to be tough*
*只可惜你的外殼不如我堅硬*
*But your armor's just not hard enough*
*毛伊  該換我踢你屁股了*
*Maui Now it's time to kick your heinie*
*從沒見過這么耀眼的我吧*
*Ever seen someone so shiny*
*死之前再好好看吧*
*Soak it in 'cause it's the last you'll ever see*
*這就是人生  我的朋友*
*C'est la vie mon ami*
*我如此閃耀*
*I'm so shiny*
*盤中餐快寫好遺愿吧*
*Now I eat you so prepare your final plea*
*只能求我*
*Just for me*
*你永遠不會這么閃亮*
*You'll never be quite as shiny*
*你會希望你也能閃亮又美麗的*
*You wish you were nice and shiny*
我有個閃亮的東西給你
I got something shiny for ya!
特菲提之心
The heart of Te Fiti.
你逃不出我的手掌的
You can't run from me!
好吧你跑了  還真是一直給我驚喜啊
Oh, you can. You keep surprising me.
你的兩條小短腿只能跑到這里了
There's only so far you can get on those two little legs.
創造一切的力量
The power of creation...
歸屬于身披甲殼的我啦
for a crustacean.
去哪兒了  去哪兒了
Where is it? Where is it?
快走
We gotta go!
那顆心怎么辦
What about the heart?
就讓他拿著吧  我有顆更好的
He can have it. I've got a better one.
太好了  我得到了
Yes, I have the...
等一下
Wait a minute.
我懂了  她把藤壺
I see, she's taken a barnacle
涂滿發光藻  來糊弄我
and she's covered it in bioluminescent algae as a diversion.
給我回來
Come back here!
那首歌你們還喜歡嗎
Did you like the song?
我們還活著
We're alive!
聽著
Listen...
我很感謝你在下面所做的一切
I appreciate what you did down there.
那需要很大的勇氣
Took guts.
不過呢
But...
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我難得這么認真地講心里話
I'm trying to be sincere for once,
但你似乎總是注意力不集中
and it feels like you're distracted.
沒有  才沒有  不會啦
No, no. No way!
是嗎  可你看我的眼神就好像我長了個...
Really? Because you're looking at me like I have a...
鯊魚頭
shark head.
什么  你有個鯊魚頭嗎
What? Do you have a shark head?
聽著  重點是
Look, the point is...
對于一個小女孩  小屁孩  之類的
for a little girl, child, thing, whatever...
之前根本沒下去過
who had no business being down there...
你幫了我一個大忙
you did me a solid.
但你也差點死掉
But you also almost died.
我也差點輸給那只蠢螃蟹
And I couldn't even beat that dumb crab.
至于打敗特卡的勝算
So, chances of beating Te Ka?
約等于零
Bupkis.
我們永遠到不了特菲提
We're never making it to Te Fiti.
這一次任務被詛咒了
This mission is cursed.
沒有被詛咒
It's not cursed.
鯊魚頭
Shark head.
這并不是詛咒
It is not cursed.
被詛咒了
Cursed.
*我能說的只有一句*
*What can I say except*
*我們快死啦*
*We're dead soon*
你就不能試試嗎
Can you at least try?
巨鷹
Giant hawk.
*沒關系  沒關系  反正也快死了*
*Hey, it's okay, it's okay we're dead soon*
好了  休息時間結束
All right, break time's over.
起來
Get up.
怎么  你要灌我心靈雞湯嗎
Why? Are you gonna give me a speech?
告訴我我能打敗特卡  就因為我是"毛伊"
Tell me I can beat Te Ka 'cause I'm "Maui?"
哪涼快那歇著去  小不點
Take a hike, Tiny.
你的紋身是怎么來的
How do you get your tattoos?
我完成一件壯舉  他們便會自己出現
They show up. When I earn them.
那這個又是怎么來的呢
How'd you earn that one? What's that for?
是因為發現"不你事"
That's man's discovery of Nunya.
"不你事"是什么
What's Nunya?
不關你的事兒
Nunya business.
那我只好繼續問了
I'll just keep asking.
這個是怎么來的
What's it for?
別鬧了
You need to stop doing that.
-滾開  -告訴我這是怎么來的嘛
- Back off. - Just tell me what it is.
我說了滾開
I said back off.
所以你的魚鉤才不起作用嗎
Is it why your hook's not working?
你不想開口  就別開口了
You don't wanna talk, don't talk.
你想把我扔下船
You wanna throw me off the boat...
就扔我下去吧
throw me off.
你想告訴我  我不知道自己在做什么
You wanna tell me I don't know what I'm doing...
我的確不知道
I know I don't.
我完全不知道為什么大海選擇了我
I have no idea why the ocean chose me.
你是對的
You're right.
但我的島嶼正在消亡
But my island is dying...
所以我來到了這兒
so I am here.
這里只有我和你
It's just me and you.
我想幫你
And I want to help...
但你若拒絕幫助  我也無能為力
but I can't if you don't let me.
我并非生來就是半神
I wasn't born a demigod.
我的父母都是人類
I had human parents.
他們
They uh...
他們看了我一眼
They took one look and decided...
然后決定遺棄我
they did not want me.
他們把我扔進了海里
They threw me into the sea...
好像我無關緊要
like I was nothing.
機緣巧合下  我被眾神發現了
Somehow, I was found by the gods.
眾神給了我魚鉤
They gave me the hook.
眾神讓我成為了
They made me...
毛伊
Maui.
我回到了人類世界中
And back to the humans I went.
我為人類帶來島嶼  火和椰子
I gave them islands, fire, coconuts.
他們想要的所有東西
Anything they could ever want.
你是為他們才偷走心石的
You took the heart for them.
你所做的一切都是為了他們
You did everything for them.
為了他們能愛戴你
So they'd love you.
而他們永不滿足
It was never enough.
也許眾神發現你是有原因的
Maybe the gods found you for a reason.
也許是大海把你帶給了他們
Maybe the ocean brought you to them...
因為它認為你值得救
because it saw someone who was worthy of being saved.
但并不是眾神讓你成為了毛伊
But the gods aren't the ones who make you Maui.
你才是
You are.
好啦好啦
Okay, okay.
我也愛你  兄弟
I love you, too, buddy.
下一站  特菲提
Next stop, Te Fiti.
怎么
What?
我想明白了
I figured it out.
大海曾經很喜歡我從海面升起島嶼
You know, the ocean used to love when I pulled up islands...
這樣你的祖先們就能駛過海洋去找了
'cause your ancestors would sail her seas and find 'em.
所有那些新的土地  新的村莊
All those new lands, new villages.
是海水讓他們連接起來
It was the water that connected 'em all.
如果我是海洋
And if I were the ocean...
我想我也會找一個卷發的非公主
I think I'd be looking for a curly-haired non-princess...
讓這一切重新來過
to start that again.
這真的是你對我講過的最友好的話
That is literally the nicest thing you've ever said to me.
也許該留到我們到了特菲提再說
Probably should have saved it for Te Fiti.
到了
I did.
莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
Moana of Motunui...
我相信
I believe you have
你已真正帶毛伊穿洋過海
officially delivered Maui across the great sea.
莫阿娜  莫阿娜  莫阿娜
Moana! Moana! Moana!
你真了不起
You're so amazing!
是時候了
It's time.
去拯救世界吧
Go save the world.
毛伊
Maui!
你要干什么
What are you doing?
幫你找到一條更好的路
Finding you a better way in!
-不會成功的  -會的
- We won't make it! - Yes, we will!
-掉頭  -不
- Turn around! - No!
莫阿娜  停下
Moana, stop!
不
No!
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
毛伊
Maui?
我告訴過你  掉頭
I told you to turn back.
我以為我們能成功
I thought we could make it.
我們
We?
我以為我能成功
I thought I could make it.
我們能修好它
We can fix it.
這是眾神做的
It was made by the gods.
修不了
You can't fix it!
下一次我們會更小心的
Next time we'll be more careful.
特卡被困在礁島上
Te Ka was stuck on the barrier islands.
它是熔巖  不能入水
It's lava, it can't go in the water.
我們能找條路繞過去
We can find a way around.
我不會回去的
I'm not going back.
我們還是得歸還心石
We still have to restore the heart.
我的魚鉤裂了
My hook is cracked.
再撞一次  就完了
One more hit, and it's over.
毛伊  你必須歸還心石
Maui, you have to restore the heart.
沒有魚鉤  我就什么也不是了
Without my hook, I am nothing.
這不是真的
That's not true!
沒有魚鉤  我就什么也不是了
Without my hook, I am nothing!
我們會在這兒
We are only here...
都是因為你當初偷了這塊心石
because you stole the heart in the first place.
不  我們在這兒是因為大海說你是特別的
No, we're here because the ocean told you you're special...
而且你相信了
and you believed it.
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
-你要跟我上船  -再見  莫阿娜
- You will board my boat... - Goodbye, Moana.
穿過大海
...sail across the sea...
我不想自取滅亡
I'm not killing myself...
就為了讓你證明你并不是的虛妄
so you can prove you're something you're not!
歸還特菲提之心
...and restore the heart of Te Fiti!
大海選擇了我
The ocean chose me!
它選錯了
It chose wrong.
毛伊
Maui!
為什么你把我帶到這兒
Why did you bring me here?
我不是正確人選
I'm not the right person.
你必須選擇別人了
You have to choose someone else.
選擇別人吧
Choose someone else.
拜托了
Please.
不
No.
你現在可離環礁遠遠的了
You're a long ways past the reef.
奶奶
Gramma?
我真是選對了紋身
Guess I chose the right tattoo.
奶奶
Gramma!
我試過了  奶奶
I tried, Gramma.
我做不到
I...I couldn't do it.
這不是你的錯
It's not your fault.
我不該給你這樣沉重的壓力
I never should have put so much on your shoulders.
如果你想回家
If you are ready to go home...
我會陪你一起
I will be with you.
你為什么猶豫了呢
Why do you hesitate?
我不知道
I don't know.
*我認識一個小島上的女孩*
*I know a girl from an island*
*她與眾不同*
*She stands apart from the crowd*
*她愛海洋  也愛她的族人*
*She loves the sea and her people*
*她讓整個家族驕傲*
*She makes her whole family proud*
*有時世界像是故意為難*
*Sometimes the world seems against you*
*旅程讓人受傷*
*The journey may leave a scar*
*但是傷痕愈合  并提醒你*
*But scars can heal and reveal just*
*你身處何方*
*Where you are*
*你因愛的人改變*
*The people you love will change you*
*學到的將為你指路*
*The things you have learned will guide you*
*但一切都不能平息*
*And nothing on earth can silence*
*你心底的那個聲音*
*The quiet voice still inside you*
*當那個聲音開始悄聲訴說*
*And when that voice starts to whisper*
*莫阿娜  你都走到這一步了*
*Moana, you've come so far*
*莫阿娜  聽啊*
*Moana, listen*
*你知道你是誰嗎*
*Do you know who you are?*
我是誰
Who am I?
*我是深愛我的小島的女孩*
*I am a girl who loves my island*
*我也深愛著大海*
*And the girl who loves the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*It calls me*
*我是酋長的女兒*
*I am the daughter of the village chief*
*我們是航海者的后裔*
*We are descended from voyagers*
*他們穿越海洋  尋找方向*
*Who found their way across the world*
*他們呼喚著我*
*They call me*
*我帶我們跋涉至此*
*I've delivered us to where we are*
*我去過遠方*
*I have journeyed farther*
*我不僅是我所學的一切*
*I am everything I've learned and more*
*有聲音在呼喚我*
*Still it calls me*
*這聲音不是來自外部*
*And the call isn't out there at all*
*而是在我心底*
*It's inside me*
*如潮水般*
*It's like the tide*
*漲漲落落*
*Always falling and rising*
*我將把你珍藏心底*
*I will carry you here in my heart*
*時刻提醒著我*
*You remind me*
*不管前路如何*
*That come what may*
*我知道方向*
*I know the way*
*我是莫阿娜*
*I am Moana*
我是莫圖魯尼島的莫阿娜
I am Moana of Motunui.
跟我上船
Aboard my boat...
我將穿過大海
I will sail across the sea...
歸還特菲提之心
and restore the heart of Te Fiti.
特卡不能隨我們入水
Te Ka can't follow us into the water.
要是我們能駛過礁島
We make it past the barrier islands...
我們就能到達特菲提
we make it to Te Fiti.
你一點都不明白我在說什么
None of which you understand...
因為你是只雞
because you are a chicken.
不
No!
憨憨  不不不
Heihei! No, no, no!
干得好
Nice work!
特菲提
Te Fiti.
毛伊
Maui!
你回來了
You came back.
但你的魚鉤
But your hook.
再撞一次它就...
One more hit and...
特卡得先抓住我才行
Te Ka's gotta catch me first.
我掩護你  被選中的人
I got your back, Chosen One.
去拯救世界吧
Go save the world.
毛伊
Maui.
謝謝你
Thank you.
別客氣
You're welcome.
燙燙燙  好燙好燙
Hot-hot-hot, hot-hot-hot!
特卡
Hey, Te Ka!
鯊魚頭
Shark head!
莫阿娜
Moana!
把心石放入螺旋中
Get the heart to the spiral!
特菲提
Te Fiti...
消失了
it's gone.
特卡
Te Ka!
讓她走向我
Let her come to me.
*我穿越海平線來找你*
*I have crossed the horizon to find you*
*我知道你的名字*
*I know your name*
*他們偷了你的心*
*They have stolen the heart from inside you*
*但這不能定義你*
*But this does not define you*
*這不是真正的你*
*This is not who you are*
*你知道你是誰*
*You know who you are*
*真正的你*
*Who you truly are*
特菲提
Te Fiti!
這只雞活下來了
The chicken lives.
你的魚鉤  我很遺憾
I'm sorry about your hook.
有沒有魚鉤
Well, hook, no hook...
我都是毛伊
I'm Maui.
特菲提
Te Fiti!
你過得好嗎
Hey, I mean, how you been?
我所做過的事
Look, what I did was...
是錯的
wrong.
沒有借口
I have no excuse.
對不起
I'm sorry.
不接受女神的禮物可是不禮貌的哦
You know, it'd be rude to refuse a gift from a goddess.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我非常感激你的好意
Your kind gesture is deeply appreciated.
我會想你的  小雞腿
Gonna miss you, drumstick.
你可以和我們一起走
You could come with us, you know.
我的族人需要一位規劃導航大師
My people are going to need a master wayfinder.
他們已經有一位了
They already have one.
再會了  毛伊
See you out there, Maui.
再會了  莫阿娜
See you out there, Moana.
媽媽  爸爸
Mom! Dad!
莫阿娜
Moana!
我可能稍微有點越過環礁了
I may have gone a little ways past the reef.
這才是你
It suits you.
她回來了
She's back!
胖胖
Pua!
歡迎回家
Welcome home!
*我們啟航漫游*
*We set a course to find*
*尋找新的家園*
*A brand new island everywhere we roam*
*故土永在心中*
*We keep our island in our mind*
*念時即能歸鄉*
*And when it's time to find home we know the way*
*我們是解讀一切的探險家*
*We are explorers reading every sign*
*我們的故事世代相傳  永不終結*
*We tell the stories of our elders in a never-ending chain*
*我們認得回家的路*
*We know the way*
海洋奇緣
*從很久前我就喜歡眺望*
*I've been staring at the edge of the water*
*海平面的盡頭*
*Long as I can remember*
*卻從不明白原因*
*Never really knowing why*
*我希望能做個聽話的女兒*
*I wish I could be the perfect daughter*
*但無論我如何努力*
*But I come back to the water*
*都還是回到這海洋*
*No matter how hard I try*
*經過每個轉彎  走過每條小徑*
*Every turn I take, every trail I track*
*踏過每條小路  都引領我回到*
*Every path I make, every road leads back*
*那個我不能去*
*To the place I know where I cannot go*
*卻無比向往的地方*
*Where I long to be*
*看那海天相接*
*See the line where the sky meets the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*It calls me*
*有誰知道*
*And no one knows*
*它延伸到多遠*
*How far it goes*
*如果海風助我  揚帆起航*
*If the wind in my sail on the sea stays behind me*
*我終會知道*
*One day I'll know*
*若我啟程  前途無限*
*If I go, there's just no telling how far I'll go*
*我知道這座島上的每個人*
*I know everybody on this island*
*似乎對島上生活快樂無憂*
*Seems so happy on this island*
*一切早已安排好*
*Everything is by design*
*我知道這座島上的每個人*
*I know everybody on this island*
*都有自己的在島上的職責*
*Has a role on this island*
*所以或許我也該坦然接受*
*So maybe I can roll with mine*
*我可以驕傲地領導  讓部族更強*
*I can lead with pride I can make us strong*
*若我遵循傳統  應該也會心滿意足*
*I'll be satisfied if I play along*
*但心里卻一直唱著另一首歌*
*But the voice inside sings a different song*
*我這是怎么了*
*What is wrong with me*
*看遠方海上陽光閃耀*
*See the light as it shines on the sea*
*令人目眩*
*It's blinding*
*有誰知道*
*But no one knows*
*它能照到多深*
*How deep it goes*
*似乎在呼喚我*
*And it seems like it's calling out to me*
*來找我吧*
*So come find me*
*我想知道*
*And let me know*
*海平線外面的世界  我能否穿過海平線*
*What's beyond that line will I cross that line*
*看那海天相接*
*The line where the sky meets the sea*
*它呼喚著我*
*It calls me*
*有誰知道*
*And no one knows*
*它延伸到多遠*
*How far it goes*
*如果海風助我  揚帆起航*
*If the wind in my sail on the sea stays behind me*
*我終會知道*
*One day I'll know*
*我將遠行何方*
*How far I'll go*
先別急著關  1小時46分還有一點點
*閃耀*
*Shiny*
*我如此閃耀*
*I'm so shiny*
光唱也沒什么用
Didn't help me though, did it?
我還是肚皮朝上
Still upside down here.
就只需要推我一下下
Just need a little push.
拜托
Can we be real?
《小美人魚》中的螃蟹
如果我叫塞巴斯蒂安
If my name was Sebastian
還有酷酷的牙買加口音的話
and I had a cool Jamaican accent...
你一定會幫我的
you'd totally help me.
你會的  你一定會的
You would. You know you would.